♪〜
〜♪
Vash!
（レム･セイブレム）
ヴァッシュ ヴァッシュ！
Wake up, quick!
起きて 早く
Oh, Vash...
もう ヴァッシュったら…
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
うっ ああ… レム
Rem...
あっ ああ…
うっ ああ…
ああ…
ハッ
ハア ハア…
ハア ハア ハア ハア…
ハア ハア ハア…
W-What have I done?
ぼ… 僕は
（メリル･ストライフ）
本当にありがとうございました
Thank you for all of your help.
He might not have
made it otherwise.
おかげで助かりましたわ
Think nothing of it. If you
need anything else, just ask.
（男）いいってことよ
何か困ったことがあれば
また言いな
（メリル）はい
ありがとうございます
I will, thank you.
（メリル）あっ！
Oh! You're awake!
あっ… あら
気がついたんですのね
よかったですわ
That's a relief. I'll fix
you some soup right away!
今すぐ
スープの支度をしますわ
Where are we?
（ヴァッシュ）ここは どこだい？
It's a small village
about 200 iles from LR.
（メリル）エルアールから
200アイルほど離れた—
小さな村ですわ
The villagers lent us this house
so we could care for your wounds.
重傷を負ったあなたのために—
村の人たちが
この家を貸してくださったんです
覚えてます？
Do you remember? You've been asleep
for 10 days straight since we got here.
あなた ここに来てから
10日間も眠りっぱなしでしたのよ
Here, drink this.
さあ これを飲んで
栄養つけてくださいね
You need nourishment.
I...
僕は…
I remember, I...
僕は あのとき…
あっ あー いけない！
Oh, I almost forgot!
私 用事がありましたの
I need to be somewhere!
I'd better hurry.
ああ 急がないと
（ドアが開く音）
Finish all of your soup, okay?
スープ ちゃんと飲んでくださいね
（ドアが閉まる音）
Mr. Vash...
（メリル）ヴァッシュさん
（ヴァッシュ）うう… うわあっ
ああ… ああーっ
うわあっ！ ああーっ！
うわあーっ！
Miss Meryl?
（老人）メリルさん メリルさんや
How is your friend doing?
お連れさんの具合はどうかね？
（メリル）あ… はい
Much better, thank you.
He's regained consciousness.
おかげさまで
意識を取り戻しました
I think he should be
up and about soon.
もう少しすれば—
起き上がれるようになると
思いますわ
That's wonderful!
I'm happy to hear that.
（老人）そうか そうか
そら よかった
（老人･メリル）ううっ
（メリルの悲鳴）
Sorry about that!!
（ミリィ･トンプソン）
すみませーん！
（メリル）えっ？
（ミリィ）エヘヘヘヘ…
Mr. Vash is awake?!
That's wonderful!
そうですか！
ヴァッシュさん
気がついたんですね
（メリル）ええ
Yes.
That's great!
よかったですね
That reminds me, ma'am!
Here are today's earnings.
あっ そうそう 先輩
これ 今日のお手当です
I'm sorry about
making you do all this.
ごめんなさいね
あなたにまで
こんなことをさせてしまって
Don't worry about me!
I always worked the fields at home...
平気ですよ
実家では
ずっと畑仕事してましたし
それに体を動かしてるほうが—
...and besides, if I keep busy,
I don't have to think about stuff.
いろんなことを考えなくて
済みますから
T-That reminds me.
How is the well?
そ… そういえば
井戸のほうは どうですの？
By the schedule, we should reach
the water vein in one week.
予定なら あと１週間ぐらいで
地下水脈にたどり着けるそうですよ
All right, let's splurge
on dinner tonight!
よし！ 夕食は
ちょっと奮発しましょっか
Do you mean it?!
ホントですか？
（ドアの開閉音）
Come again!
（店主）まいど どうも！
This place kind of reminds me
of my home town.
（ミリィ）この町を見てると
なんだか田舎を思い出します
Was your home like this?
（メリル）ミリィの実家も
こんな感じでしたの？
That's right! It's a quiet,
plain little village.
はい
静かで なーんもない村でした
でも 家族がいたから
とても楽しかったです
But it was really great
because my family was there.
Family...
家族…
あっ
Ma'am?
先輩？
あの人…
It's him.
Just past there.
（ヴァッシュ）
あの向こうに やつが…
Knives is just past there, but...
ナイヴズがいるというのに…
After so long, I'm so
close to finding him, but...
ずっと捜し続けてきた
やつがいるというのに…
Answer me one thing!
（ニコラス･Ｄ･ウルフウッド）
１つだけ聞かせい
What do you intend to do
once you see Knives?
お前 ナイヴズに会(お)うたら
どないするつもりや？
He stole someone
I loved from me.
（ヴァッシュ）あいつは
俺から大切な人を奪った
Do you want revenge?
（ウルフウッド）復讐(ふくしゅう)か？
I don't know.
（ヴァッシュ）
分からない… 分からないんだ
I don't know!
I see.
So that's how you live.
（ウルフウッド）そうか
そうやって生きていくんやな
That's how you chose to live.
そういう生き方を選んだんやな
Wolfwood...
（ヴァッシュ）ウルフウッド
...what should I do
when I see Knives?
やつに会ったとき
僕はどうすればいい？
I killed a man
with my own hand.
この手で人をあやめた僕が
やつに何を言える？
What can I possibly
say to him?
I'm no different.
同じだよ
Rem... Rem...
レム　レム…
I'm sorry, Rem...
I went wrong...
ごめんね レム
僕は間違ってしまった
I made a mistake...
過ちを犯してしまった
うう…
（すすり泣き）
Mr. Vash?
（メリル）ヴァッシュさん
何してるんですか？
What are you doing up here?
Your wounds haven't closed yet.
まだ傷口は
ふさがってないんですのよ
（ヴァッシュ）ああっ！
（メリル）ヴァッシュさん！
Mr. Vash!
You shouldn't strain yourself!
ダメですよ まだ無理しちゃ
I have to go...
（ヴァッシュ）い… 行かなきゃ
Go? Where,
in your condition?!
行く？
そんな体で どこへ行くんですか！
Rem...
I have to go to Rem.
レム… レムの所に
What are you saying?
な… 何を言ってるんですの？
I'm going to where Rem is.
レムの所に行くんだ
I'm going to...
レムの…
Snap out of it!
（メリル）しっかりしてください
（ミリィ）ヴァッシュさん…
Mr. Vash!
Let me go! I'm...
（ヴァッシュ）離してくれ
僕は もう戻れない
I can never go back.
I killed a man.
人を殺した
I took someone's life!
僕は 人の命を奪ったんだ
But there was no other...
でも あの場合は…
Don't tell me
there was no other way.
しかたなかったなんて
言わないでくれ
There had to be
a way to save everyone.
誰も死なずに済んだ方法が
あったはずなんだ
Even Rem said so.
There had to be a way.
レムは言ったもの
きっと あるって
Rem, tell me.
Did I?
レム 教えて　僕は…
（倒れる音）
Mr. Vash!
ヴァッシュさん
Mr. Vash!!
ヴァッシュさん！
We shouldn't have
followed him after all.
やっぱり ついてきては
いけなかったんですわ
Huh?!
（ミリィ）えっ？
If only I hadn't followed him,
it might have turned out differently.
そうすれば あのときも—
違う結果になっていた
かもしれないのに
Then, he...
そうすれば この人が
こんなに苦しむこともなかったのに
...he wouldn't have had
to suffer like this!
You're wrong!!
（ミリィ）違います！
You wanted to be with him,
didn't you?
先輩は ヴァッシュさんと
一緒にいたいと思ったんでしょ？
What's wrong with
acting with your heart?
その気持ちのままに行動して
何がいけないんですか！
My big sister told me
that I should never hold back.
大姉(おおねえ)ちゃんが言ってました
“我慢したらダメだ”って
Milly...
ミリィ
Maybe I should call you "ma'am."
どっちが後輩なんだか…
（ミリィ）えっ？
It... It's nothing!
な… なんでもありませんわ
Milly, prepare to work
your butt off tomorrow, too!
ミリィ あしたからも
バリバリ働きますわよ
（ミリィ）フフッ はい
Yes, ma'am!
Ow.
（メリル）あ…
ハア…
Mr. Vash, mind the house
while we're gone.
（メリル）ヴァッシュさん
留守をお願いしますわね
（ヴァッシュ）うん
Right.
See you later!
（ミリィ）いってきまーす！
Mr. Vash looks a little happier now,
don't you think?
少し 元気に
なったんじゃないですか？
ヴァッシュさん
（メリル）ウフッ そうですわね
That's true.
（黒猫の鳴き声）
（ヴァッシュ）痛(いて)っ！
（車のエンジン音）
Hey there! You're late.
よう 遅かったじゃねえか
（ペトリ）のんきなこと言うなよ
You don't know
how lucky you are.
You guys probably
don't know this...
あんたらは知らねえだろうが—
...but a lot of weird shit
has been going on in this area.
この辺りじゃ
事件続きだったんだぜ
Did something happen?
なんかあったのか？
There have been mass disappearances
in 12 towns, and LR is a war zone.
12の町の人間が集団失踪(しっそう)して
エルアールでは盛大なドンパチだ
My family disappeared with them.
俺の家族も消えちまった
I had no idea...
そんなことが…
This is about the only
peaceful town left.
（ペトリ）平穏なのは
もう この町ぐらいなもんさ
そらよ
- There you go.
- Th-Thanks.
あっ ああ…
うん？
I haven't seen him before.
見ねえ顔だな
Oh, yeah.
About 10 days ago...
ああ… 10日くらい前だったか—
...he was brought here
by a pair of girls.
２人組の女の子に
連れられてきたのさ
He was in horrible shape,
full of holes like Swiss cheese.
ひどい状態だったぜ
体じゅうに何発もくらっててよ
（ペトリ）ふーん…
（サイモン）なっ ああ…
That blond guy looks familiar...
あの金髪…
Come on, let's get out of here!!
（サイモン）おい 行くぞ！
おっ…
どうした？ いきなり
Why all the shouting, man?
Just get in!!
ああ… いいから 早く！
Why the hurry?!
なに 慌ててんだよ？
（サイモン）ヴァ…
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードだ
Th-That was
V-Vash the Stampede!
What?!
ああ？
I'm sure of it!
The blond sitting there...
（サイモン）間違いねえ
あそこにいた金髪野郎は—
...is the Humanoid Typhoon!
ヒューマノイド･タイフーンだ！
ああ…
♪ So
So...
... on the first evening...
♪ １つ目の夜に
... a pebble from somewhere...
♪ いずこから小石が
世界に落ちる
... drops upon the world.
So...
（メリル）♪ So
♪ ２つ目の夜に
... on the second evening...
... the children of the pebble
join hands...
♪ 小石の子が手を取り
... and compose a waltz.
♪ ワルツを描(か)く
That's a nice song.
いい歌ですわね
Yeah.
（ヴァッシュ）うん
You can...
（メリル）ずっと…
（ヴァッシュ）うん？
You can stay here
permanently if you like.
（メリル）ずっと
ここにいても いいんですのよ
That sounds good.
（ヴァッシュ）いいね
That might not be so bad.
それも いいかもね
（ドアの開閉音）
I'm sorry I'm late!
I was up too late...
（メリル）すみません 遅くなって
昨日 夜更かししすぎて…
Ma'am!!
（ミリィ）先輩！
（メリル）えっ？
Ma'am...
先輩…
I'll kill him!
（ティルス）
殺してやる… 殺してやるぞ！
I'll kill that bastard!!
あ…
You really had us fooled!
（男Ａ）ヘッ
まんまと だまされたぜ
Wh-What are you talking about?
（メリル）
な… 何のことですの？
Don't play dumb with us!!!
（男Ｂ）とぼけんじゃねえや！
You brought THE
Vash the Stampede into our town!!
（男Ｃ）
あんたたちの連れてきたのが—
まさか あの
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードとはな
Please, calm down!
落ち着いてください
（老人）なあ…
わしら 死にたくないんじゃ
Listen, we don't want to die.
（メリル）えっ？
Please leave immediately.
If you do, we'll let you live.
今すぐ ここから出ていってくれ
そうすれば命は保証する
Though we can't say
as much for the guy!
（男Ｄ）ヘッ
あの男はどうか知らねえがな
Enough!
よさんか！
What do you mean?
どういうことですの？
Don't tell me...
まさか…
（車のエンジン音）
ああ…
Mr. Vash!!
ヴァッシュさん！
（ヴァッシュ）うう…
Well?! Did you feel
some of their pain?!
（ティルス）どうだよ！
てめえのせいで
死んでいったやつらの痛みを—
The pain of those
who died because of you?!
少しは感じたか！
（ヴァッシュ）うう…
ああ…
Why don't you say anything
in your defense?!
なんで 何も言い返さねえんだよ
Make some kind of an excuse!!
言い訳のひとつでも
してみろってんだ！
（ヴァッシュのせき込み）
Hey... do you think
maybe it's not him?
おい… もしかして
こいつ違うんじゃねえのか？
Yeah. Vash would never
be such a wimp.
ああ… こんな腰抜けのはずがねえ
I...
（ヴァッシュ）ぼ… 僕は
僕は…
I am...
...Vash the Stampede.
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードだ
You're right about me.
I'm a...
君の言うとおりだ
僕は…
I'm nothing but a killer.
僕は ただの…
人殺しだ
Shameless bastard!!!
（ティルス）
開き直ってんじゃねえ！
（銃声）
You're going to pay for everyone
who lived in this town!!!
この町に住んでいた
すべての人間の敵(かたき)だ！
Smile.
笑え
I'll at least let you die like a man!
せめて人間らしく死なせてやる
Smile, you shit!!
笑え クソ野郎！
I said, smile!
笑えってんだよ
Stop it!! Please!!!
やめてーっ お願い！
This man fought
to protect everyone!
この人は 皆さんを守るために
戦っていたんです
It's the truth!
Please believe me!!
本当なんです 信じてください
That's not funny!!
（ティルス）冗談じゃねえや
Ma'am!
（ミリィ）先輩！
Could a normal human being
do all those things?!
（ティルス）普通の人間に
あんな事件が起こせるか！
It has to be his doing!!
すべて こいつの仕業に
決まってるだろうが
You're wrong!!
違います！
Then, why...
だったら なぜ…
...why did Stefan
die so horribly?!
なぜ ステファンは
あんなむごい死に方をした！
Answer me!
答えろ！
答えろ
I've...
（メリル）ずっと…
I have watched him
for a long time.
ずっと見てきましたから
分かります
It's true that this man
can't avoid fighting.
この人は 確かに
戦いから逃れられない
But this man knows how
to live as a human being.
でも この人は知っています
人として生きることを
（銃声）
Don't feed me your garbage!!
（ティルス）ざれ言をほざくな！
We have a right
to shoot this monster!
俺たちには
その化け物を撃つ資格がある
We lost our friends, families,
and neighbors!!
家族を 友人を 隣人を失った
We have a right
to hate him!!!
俺たちは
こいつを恨む権利があるんだ
誰も 人の命を奪う権利なんて
ありませんわ
No one has the right
to take the life of another.
うっ
No one...
（メリル）
誰も 命を奪う権利なんて…
...has the right
to take the life...
ない！
...of another!
Everyone has a future.
みんな
未来を持っているんですもの
（ヴァッシュ）あ…
ああ…
あっ
レム
Rem...
Isn't that right?
そうですよね？
Stay back!
う… 来るな
I said, stay back!!
来るなってんだよ！
Stop.
（メリル）もう…
Stop the fighting.
もう 争わないで
Why?!
（ティルス）なんで…
なんで そんなことすんだよ！
Why are you doing this?!
If we don't stop
the hate and sorrow sometime...
憎しみも悲しみも
どこかで断ち切らないと—
...we will never
make any progress.
前に進むことはできませんわ
We weren't born to steal,
were we?
私たちは 奪うために
生きてきたわけじゃないでしょ？
ああ…
How could you two
be so reckless?
（ヴァッシュ）
なんて無茶をするんだ 君たちは
（メリル）あ… あなたに
言われたくありませんわよ
You're the last one
who should criticize.
It's exactly what
you've always done.
ヴァッシュさんは ずっと
こうしてきたじゃないですか
I'm sure it's...
きっと…
I'm sure it's what he
would have done, too.
きっと あの人も
そうしたかったんだと思います
That's it.
そうなんだ
（メリル）えっ？
That must be it!
きっと そうなんだ
えっ ちょ… ちょっと
何をするんですの？
Hey, w-wait!
What are you doing?!
ああ…
People have many different
ways of thinking.
（ヴァッシュ）
人には いろんな考え方がある
Even if you make a mistake...
もし過ちを犯したとしても—
間違いに気付けば正すことはできる
... if you realize it was a mistake,
it's always possible to fix it!
Then if you turn around,
you will see the future!
振り向けば そこに未来がある
This wisdom must be
realized for oneself.
そのことを
自分で気付かないといけない
Rem...
レム
H-Hey, how long are
you going to do that?!
ちょ… ちょっと
いつまでやってるんですの？
Damn, I'm moved to bits!!
（ヴァッシュ）
くーっ 感激した
ええ…
Let go of me!
Let go of me, you big ape!
放しなさい！
放しなさいってば！
（ヴァッシュ）うーん…
（メリル）うわあっ
（ヴァッシュ）ジョリジョリ…
（メリル）うわーっ！
（殴る音）
（メリル）ぬあ〜
Hey, I'm injured, remember?
ケガ人だよ 僕…
The red flower Rem loved...
（ヴァッシュ）
レムが好きだった赤い花
... the geranium.
ゼラニウム
... in the language
of flowers, means...
花言葉は…
“決意”
...determination.
I made it.
（ミリオンズ･ナイヴズ）
俺が作ったんだ
This one's yours.
お前の分だよ
So, you're going?
（メリル）行くんですのね？
Yeah.
（ヴァッシュ）ああ
I'll be all right now.
僕はもう 大丈夫だから
See you later.
いってらっしゃい
Uh-huh. Thanks.
うん ありがとう
あ…
- I...
- Mr. Vash!!
（ミリィ）ヴァッシュさーん！
あっ？
- Hey, that's...
- Take this with you!
それは…
持ってってください
I think it would make
Mr. Wolfwood happy!
ウルフウッドさんも
きっと喜ぶと思います
フフ… いいのかい？
Are you sure?
Sure!
はい！
おっ け… 結構 重いね
Th-This is pretty heavy.
Of course!
当然です
That's because it's
so full of mercy!
慈悲が
ぎょうさん詰まってますから
Well, I'm off!
じゃあ 行ってくるから
（メリル）何も…
I couldn't...
何も言えなかった 私
I couldn't say anything.
So tell him when he gets back!
帰ってきたら
言えばいいじゃないですか
Say everything!
思いっきり！
（レム）
ヴァッシュ　ナイヴズを…
Vash, take care of Knives.
I finally understand.
（ヴァッシュ）やっと分かったよ
I finally understand the last thing
she tried to tell me.
彼女が最後に
言おうとしていた言葉が
I will never go wrong again.
俺は 二度と間違わない
Humans are survivors.
So, I will take care of him.
人は生き抜くものなんだ
だから 俺は やつを…
I will save Knives.
ナイヴズを…
♪〜
〜♪
One day, 130 years ago...
（ヴァッシュ）
130年前 あの日 あのとき—
僕たちは生まれてきたよね
...you and I were born.
There were nothing but peaceful days,
and Rem was always close behind us.
穏やかな日々が続き—
僕たちの後ろには
いつもレムがいた
But our disagreeing thoughts
changed our ways of life.
でも すれ違ってしまった思いは
生き方を変えたね
I don't regret it.
I will vow once again...
後悔はしていないよ
僕はもう一度 誓う
...not to kill,
not to betray...
人を殺さないことを
人を裏切らないことを
...to find happiness,
to talk about my dreams...
幸せをつかむことを
夢を語ることを
...because the ticket to the future
is always unwritten.
未来への切符は
いつも白紙なんだから